ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
TL
翻译
吃冰棒
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第三集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
鸽羽
约翰·厄普代克
这么大规模的游戏不可操之过急
雅达利团队和我建立了
富有成效的工作关系
我们将继续给粉丝们带来他们所渴求
且应得的引人入胜的游戏体验
我很感激雅达利对这款游戏的支持
也很期待我们日后的合作
网络游戏的未来
卡梅伦·豪伊
进入小屋
进入小屋点击这里
一窥《朝圣者》  豪伊能有多烂
我觉得你可能会
对这个感兴趣  崔普
一窥《朝圣者》  豪伊能有多烂
世上最棒的
爸爸
和他无关
It wasn't about him.
我很难过
I was sad.
我需要把悲伤发泄出来
And I needed to pour that sadness into something, and he...
而他正好在旁边
happened to be there.
我当时和他共处一室
I was in the same room as him.
我一直在想他对我说的话
I just keep thinking about everything he said to me.
你选了他
You took his side.
你爱他
You love him.
不是这样的
That's not true.
我凭什么相信你
Why should I believe you?
因为
Because...
乔这个人没法去爱
there's no loving Joe.
你根本不可能爱他
He's impossible to love.
他是个空壳
He's empty and...
时势需要他什么样  他就变成什么样
he just becomes whatever circumstance needs him to be.
你又是谁
Who are you?
乔
Joe!
真是太好了
This is perfect.
一秒钟都等不得  是不是
Didn't waste any time, did you?
他在吗
Is he here?
在办公室
At the office!
你没认真听我说
You're not hearing me.
不  这对你而言是个机会
No, this is an opportunity for you.
我们愿意重新谈条件  乔恩
We are willing to restructure the deal, Jon.
听着  你只要给我五分钟就好
Listen, just give me five minutes of your time.
戈登  我很抱歉
Gordon, I'm sorry.
我才知道发生了什么
I had no idea what was going on.
我刚和沃尔比通完电话
Just got off the phone with Volpi.
是啊  你当然能联系上他了
Of course you can get him on the line.
他完全不让步
He's not budging!
我在找太平洋贝尔
I'm trying PacBell.
那边也没得谈  你太晚了
There's nothing there. You're too late.
我们现在唯一的一步棋
The only play we have left now
就是趁还值点钱的时候赶紧卖出去
is to sell while we're still worth something.
别这么说  我们再想想办法
Don't say that. We can still figure something...
少装了  乔
Oh, spare me the theatrics, Joe.
你既然已经打了五分钟的电话  就该清楚情况了
If you've been on the phone for five minutes, then you know!
这可不是我想听你说的话
That is not what I want to hear from you right now.
卡梅伦可好啊
How's Cameron?
没错  我今早去了你家一趟
Yeah, I stopped by your place this morning.
她看起来  很惬意
She looked, uh... comfortable.
你可以想象我有多吃惊
You know, you can imagine my surprise.
你没影了  我还以为你生我气了
You disappear, I think you're upset with me,
搞了半天原来你去泡已婚妇女去了
and then turns out you've been holed up with a married woman.
她离婚了
She's divorced.
快了
Almost.
快离婚了
Almost divorced!
-真是太好了  -怎么说起卡梅伦了
- Th-That's beautiful. - Why are we talking about Cameron?
因为我了解你们两个
Because I know you two!
你们就像  就像
And it's like... it's like...
就像你是辆火车  她也是辆火车
it's like you're a train and she's a train,
然后你就想  我们俩都是火车
and you think, "Oh, we're both trains.
肯定合得来
We should get along great"!
然后两辆火车在同一条铁轨上
But then both the trains are on the same track,
朝着对方迎头撞去
and they're both headed right for each other,
你猜怎么着
and guess what...
俩车上都装满了炸药
both the trains are carrying dynamite.
这种事我见得多了
Look, I've seen this a thousand times.
我知道是什么结果
I know how it ends.
-好好好  好吧  -会爆炸的
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay. - It's gonna explode!
-我们对彼此没好处  -又不是...
- We're bad for each other... - It's not...
-早晚吃不了兜着走  -没错
- and it's going to be disastrous. - Yes!
这是什么
What is this?
我给你做了早饭
I made you breakfast.
是奶酪蛋
It's cheese egg.
奶酪蛋
Cheese egg!
我
I, uh...
真希望我今天能去
wish I could come today.
我们要去敲定出售协议的最后细节
We're putting the final details on the sale,
而且戈登有点  心碎了吧
and Gordon's a little... heartbroken, I think.
说真的  没关系的
Honestly, it's just fine.
本来也不是什么大事
It's such a non-thing.
我还是照常扮演听话的机器人
I'm gonna do my little obedient-robot routine,
然后就完事了
and that's it.
完事了你也来一趟吧
You should swing by after.
戈登会消气的
Gordon'll get over himself.
没事的  因为我还得去
It's fine anyways, 'cause I have to...
借过
excuse me.
问答会之后  我还得和雅达利谈谈
I'm having a sit-down with Atari after the panel deal
聊聊《朝圣者》下一步怎么走
to talk next steps on Pilgrim, so...
肯定会聊得很愉快吧
Oh, that should go smoothly.
是啊  我觉得他们会回心转意的
Yeah, I think they're gonna come around.
我  给你准备了个礼物
I, uh... I got a present for you.
给我
Me?
打电游的时候用
For your video games.
这可真是
Well, that's...
消极进攻啊
passive-aggressive.
真的  有吗
Really? Is it?
因为我本来是想玩直白
'Cause I was... I was aiming for blunt,
-坚决明确的  -那你没做好
- uncompromising clarity. - Oh. You missed the mark.
你太吵
You're loud.
你不管干什么都那么大声
Everything you do is loud...
-还邋里邋遢  -抱歉
- and messy. - Sorry.
倒让我想起来了
Which reminds me,
你今天应该收拾行李了
you should unpack the boxes today.
我非常抱歉打乱了你
I'm so sorry for interrupting
完美分类归置的小生活了
your perfect catalogue existence little life.
我怎么感觉你把那当做是一种侮辱呢
I feel like you, um... you thought that was an insult.
-你是个怪人你知道吗  -收拾吧
- You're a freak. You know that, right? - Unpack.
你就好像有人给了霍华德·休斯
You're like if somebody gave Howard Hughes...
-赶紧开箱  -一本《流浪者之歌》
- Unpack..Our boxes...- A copy of "Siddhartha"
而他就那么接受了
and he just rolled with it.
你就差三瓶尿
You're like three bottles of piss away
就能建立一个完美的抗菌室
from building a perfect antibacterial chamber.
你瞧  隔音效果真好嘿
See? God, these work great.
你说的话我一个字都没听见
I can't hear a word you're saying.
烦死人了你
You're so annoying.
你的车20分钟后到
Your car will be here in 20.
保险箱公司的人10点来做展示
The guys from StrongBox are presenting at 10:00.
-而且  -多链路的提议拿到了吗
- Also... - Do you have the proposal from MultiLink?
放在你桌上了  不过
It's on your desk, but...
早上好
Good morning.
音威士的人今天送来的
the guys at TuneWorx sent this in today
作为成功上市募股的谢礼
as a thank-you for the IPO.
他们知道我玩吉他
They know I play.
我和望远镜的人谈过了
I talked to the guys at Spyglass.
他们不是不接受风投吗
I thought they weren't taking VC.
如果我没看错的话
If I'm reading it right,
他们要给马赛克的代码申请专利了
they're going to license the Mosaic code,
如果他们打算接受投资的话
and if they take anyone's money,
就该是来自我们
it should be ours.
几周前你还对浏览器不感兴趣呢
Few weeks ago, you weren't interested in a browser play.
你也知道
Yeah, well, you know,
好的浏览器总是很吸引人嘛
the right browser could have legs.
我学了好几年了
Been taking lessons a couple years now.
我弹得还行
I mean, I'm a good player.
但肯定够不上大师级
I'll never be a great player.
别这么说嘛
Don't say that.
望远镜那边有消息我会通知你的
I'll keep you in the loop on Spyglass.
我们可以联手
We could tag-team it.
多谢
Thanks.
是寄给卡梅伦的箱子
Package came for Cameron.
太好了
Great.
又来东西了
More stuff.
是汤姆寄来的
It's from Tom.
还有几份
Just a couple more.
你还好吧
You okay?
我们没办法
Our hands were tied.
而且卖价很高
We sold high.
比预计的要高一倍
Got twice what we thought we would.
看来你有动力的时候
Guess you can still navigate the business world
还是能叱咤生意场的
when you're motivated.
我们有资金  可以重新开始
We've got capital, blank canvas.
我喜欢这里
I liked this place.
我知道现在没这种感觉  但是
I know it doesn't feel like it now, but...
这是一个开始
this is the start of something.
11点的预约快到了
Our 11:00 will be here soon.
好啊
What's up?
乔想和你谈谈
Joe would like to talk to you about the pro--
你做的索引
The index you made,
那个指南  彗星网址单那个
the-the-the guide, the comet list thing.
我很喜欢
I love it.
谢谢
Thanks.
更重要的是  其他人也喜欢
More importantly, other people love it.
访问量惊人
The traffic is astonishing.
没错  宝贝  这主意真的很棒
Yeah, honey, it's a really, really good idea.
这个主意  做索引  显然是我的
The idea, obviously, was mine, the indexing.
我自己人工做了很多年
I did that work by hand over years.
你爸爸是想说
What your dad means to say
对这个想法的执行非常好
is that the execution of that idea is wonderful,
我们想从你手里买下它
and we want to buy it from you.
乔  慢点来
Oh, Joe, slow down.
-乔  -我想在它的基础上构建出一个
- Joe... - I want to build it and make it into something...
真正的产品  无意冒犯
real... no offense.
我会立即把它转移到专属的服务器上
I would migrate it to its own dedicated server immediately
这样就能进行无缝交接
so there is a seamless transition,
对服务也没有影响
no interruption in service.
我今天就能做
I would do that today.
我已经做了
I did it already.
你想买下它吗
You want to buy it?
他是...乔...
What he -- Joe's, uh...
这是你做出来的
Look, you...you did the work,
所以我们自然要从你手中收购
so it's only natural that we would buy it from you.
这...是规矩
That's...that's...that's how these things work.
行啊  用多少钱买
Okay. Buy it for how much?
-我们可以从  -我觉得两万元就挺合理
- We would begin... - I think a reasonable sum would be $20,000.
你能跟我出来谈一下吗
Can I talk to you real quick?
我以为你要给她
Look, I thought you were gonna offer her, like,
像是百视达的礼品卡
a-a gift certificate to Blockbuster
或者是一百块之类的
or, like, a hundred bucks or something.
你想给你的亲女儿压这样的低价
You want to low-ball your own daughter?
不是的  乔
No, Joe.
是你说"象征性给点"好吧  她只有14岁
You said a "nominal fee," Okay? She's 14 years old.
你不能给一个14岁孩子两万块
You can't give a 14-year-old $20,000.
这个网站
This website has...
-我在捏爆你的头  -两周有一万两千的访问量
- I'm crushing your head. - 12,000 unique visitors in two weeks.
这简直难以置信
That's unbelievable.
我不管
I don't give a shit.
她才14岁
She's 14 years old.
十年后她就24了
In 10 years, she'll be 24 years old,
而这个想法可能值数十亿
and this idea could be worth a billion dollars.
我们不能给她钱
We're not giving her the money.
我们可以想别的办法  像是信托基金什么的
Okay? We can come up with another idea or a trust fund or something,
-但我们不能给她  -这主意很好
- but we're not giving a her... - Yes, that sounds great.
行  我们往一个信托基金里投两万
Yeah, we'll put $20,000 in a trust fund.
我们谈了一下
We talked.
我们想给五千块...
And we think that $5,000 --
我不想要钱
I don't want money.
我想参与进来
I want to work on it.
-成交  -什么
- Deal. - What? Wh--
我想来这里参与它的工作
I want to be able to come here and work on it
以此顶一节课
instead of going to school for one period.
-我们可以...  -就当是我的自主学习
- Well, we could -- - It can be my independent study.
没问题  我们这就确定相关事宜
No problem. We'll wire that up right away.
我知道你现在得回去上语文课
Now, I understand you have to get back to English,
所以我们等你放学再谈
so we're gonna talk about this after school.
戈登  我们在你家见
Gordon, we'll meet at your place?
好吧
Sure.
他们的防火墙有宣传得那么好吗
Is their firewall as strong as it sounds?
应用层已更新到第三代了
Third-generation, application layer.
他们很有才
They're very talented.
展览也办得很成功
Put on a good show, too.
说到作秀...
Speaking of putting on a show...
瞧瞧他
Look at him.
虽然他很怪  但是个不错的合伙人
For all his quirks, it's good he's a partner.
他能带来生意
He brings in deals.
他企图在浏览器上打压我
He's trying to outflank me on the browser front.
几周前  他把千禧浏览器损得一无是处
Few weeks ago, he shits all over Millennium.
现在他又去讨好望远镜了
Now he's cozying up to Spyglass?
他没跟我提起什么
Well, he didn't mention anything to me.
或许他只是想和你好好合作
Maybe he just wants to work with you.
尼娜·克莱因来了
There's Nina Klein.
我要去打个招呼
I should go say hi.
去吧  我要...
You go ahead. I'm gonna...
乔·利伯曼可以滚边了
Well, uh, Joe Lieberman can blow me.
《毁灭战士》只是冰山一角  好吗
Doom is just the tip of the iceberg, okay?
这就是未来  就这样
That's the future, full stop.
不对  抱歉
No. Sorry.
恐怕我不能完全赞同你的观点
I'm not sure I totally agree.
我还没玩过《毁灭战士》
Look, I haven't played Doom,
并不是因为它很暴力
but it's not because it's so violent,
而是因为在我看来  它很无聊
because to me, it seems boring.
你在说笑吧  这游戏让人上瘾
You kidding me? It's addictive.
是  它是个斯金纳箱  很多游戏都是如此
Yeah, it's a Skinner box -- a lot of these games are.
斯金纳为研究操作性条件反射而设计的实验设备
就像老虎机  能不断吸引你继续玩
They're slot machines, so they'll keep you coming back,
但并不能给你满足感
but they're not gonna fulfill you in any way.
我要说的是
Look, all I'm saying is,
我觉得未来还有空间给那些
I think there's room in the future
血腥第一视角射击游戏之外的游戏
for more than just gory, first-person shooters.
又有人要提问了
I think we have another -- another question.
我有个问题要问卡梅伦
This question's for Cameron.
我想问你能不能谈一下你的新游戏《朝圣者》
I was wondering if you could talk about your new game, Pilgrim.
我看见它的发行日期改了
I saw the release date was changed.
是的  雅达利作为合作者一直
Yeah, Atari has been a really supportive partner
都很支持这个游戏
in collaborating on this game,
他们只是想再多花点时间
and they are just taking a bit of extra time
来想一个最佳策略
to figure out the best strategy.
但是  就快了
But, um, it's coming.
我对此感到很激动
I'm excited about it.
我想你也会的
I think you will be, too.
你能不能说一个大概的完成时间呢
Do you have, like, a ballpark time when it'll be done?
已经完成了
It's done now.
至于发行  得问雅达利了
In terms of release, that would be a question for Atari.
下载游戏的好处在于
Cool thing about games you download,
在发行方面  支出少了
in terms of release, there's less overhead,
那么干预就少  所以就更血腥
which means less interference, meaning more blood.
还有人要提问吗
Do we have any other questions --
没错
Yeah, I mean...
没错  能减少一个中间人
Yeah, anytime you can cut out a middle man,
总是好事  对吗
it's a good thing, right?
就像我说的  我和雅达利关系很好
Like I said, I have a great relationship with Atari,
我们彼此都非常尊重对方
a lot of mutual respect,
但在我的职业生涯中也遇到过
but there have been times in my career
我的选择不被尊重的情况
where my choices were not as respected.
好了
W-- Okay.
如果没有其它问题的话
If there aren't, uh, any more questions,
我们今天就到这里
I think that about does it for us.
感谢诸位的光临
thank you all for coming.
感谢我们的嘉宾  汤米和
thanks to our guests, Tommy and --
我有个问题想问豪伊女士
I have a question for Ms. Howe.
你好  唐娜
Hello, Donna.
你能否谈一下
I was hoping you could talk a bit about
你作为创作者
the relationship between a creator, such as yourself,
和游戏经营方的关系
and the business side of gaming.
你之前似乎提到了
You seemed to indicate earlier
你在这方面有一些困难
that there was some difficulty for you there,
我想请问
and I was wondering if you felt
你是否觉得自身有什么责任
you had any culpability in that.
这本身就是种纠结的关系
Well, it's inherently a fraught relationship, right?
怎么说
How so?
我们有能力
Well, in that we have the ability
从无到有地进行创造
to create something out of nothing,
而这可能威胁到经营方
and that can be threatening to people on the business side
因为  他们没有这个能力
because... they can't.
就我的经验而言
Well, in my experience --
当然  我不足以成为台上
and, granted, I'm not the one up there onstage
门罗互联网战略会议的一员
at the Menlo Internet Strategy Conference...
但以我的经验  经营方的人
...but in my experience, someone on the business side
能够对处于徘徊期或者方向不正确的项目
could help shepherd a project that's meandering or...
进行引导
headed off a cliff.
可以是一个好帮手  不是吗
Could be an ally, no?
所以其实应该是一种共生关系
Seems like that relationship should be symbiotic.
我觉得是寄生关系
I would say it's parasitic.
宿主的健康与否不重要
There's little regard for the wellbeing of the host
因为寄生虫总能撤走
because a parasite can always scuttle away,
去找下一个目标
on to the next warm body.
好的
Ok-Okay.
就到这里了  我们时间有限
I think that does it. We are, uh -- We're out of time.
感谢各位的光临
Thank you all for coming.
感谢大家的提问
Thank you for your questions,
希望有机会在外面见到大家
and I hope we get a chance to meet some of you outside.
是的  我要按月支付
Well, yes, I'm going to make the monthly.
每月就发这点工资
I-I'm at the mercy of the pay schedule here.
我只是个顾问
It's a consultant position.
-怎么样  -不错
- How was -- - Fine. It was fine.
-是的  -有什么进展
- Yes. - Do we have an update?
算法在持续抓取新网页
The algorithm is continuing to pick up new pages.
正在有效地记录网络
It's effectively charting the web.
好的
Okay.
我们只能搜索网址和网页标题  但是
We're only searching URLs and page headings but --
为什么不能搜索网页内容
Why can't we search the body of the page?
这当然是最终的目标
That's the ultimate goal, of course.
-但我们还没达到那一步  -数据量太大了
- We're just not quite there yet. - It's too much data.
以现有的带宽
W-With -- With current bandwidth,
会让一切陷入停滞
everything just grinds to a halt.
我们的标题搜索效率如何
How effectively can we search titles?
效率很高
Very effectively,
但是标题不总是
but the title doesn't always correspond
和网页内容相符
with, um, what's on the site,
所以搜索结果
so the results are...
你一直在笑嘻嘻地告诉我坏消息
You keep giving me bad news with a smile on your face.
你自己知道吗
Do you know that you're doing that?
你们有全力投入吧
You guys are invested in this, right?
他们在熬夜做
Well, they have been up all night working on it.
那你们有什么成果值得展示
And what do you have to show for it?
搜索下"总统"
Let's search "president".
没有克林顿
No Clinton.
我看到的只有包含总统这个单词的结果
What I see are generic president results.
估计在这堆结果下面
My guess is that somewhere buried among them
是关于现任自由世界领袖的条目
are results about the current leader of the free world,
我想人们输入"总统"时
which is what I assume people are looking for
应该就是想找那个
when they type in "president."
我们需要一个复杂的规则引擎
What we need is a sophisticated rules engine in place.
而现在完全没有
What I see is no rules engine at all.
你们知道我以前是个工程师吧
You do know I used to be an engineer, right?
他们并不知道该做什么
They don't know what's expected of them
除非你们告诉他们
unless you tell them.
我指望你们让他们明白
I am counting on you to make it clear
他们有多短的时间把这个做好
just how little time they have to get this right.
好吗
Okay?
好了
Okay.
嗯  好
Oh, yeah. Cool.
好  调出来  我们看看
Okay. Pull it up, let's take a look.
我改了名字
I changed the header.
嗯  我喜欢  彗星
Oh, yeah. I like that. It's Comet.
听上去像呕吐
It sounds like vomit.
别听她的
Don't listen to her.
能表达出一种速度感  一种奇妙感
It conveys speed, a sense of wonder.
-这是什么  -乔和海莉
- What is this? - It's -- Joe and Haley
在做海莉的网站项目
are working on Haley's website project.
用来代替我的自主学习学分
It's replacing my independent-study credit.
什么  她可以为此不去上学吗
What? She gets to miss school for this?
我也想不上学
I want to miss school.
你是不上学
You do miss school,
但你不跟人说
you just don't tell anyone about it.
呵呵
Hardy-har-har.
我觉得  我们可以
You know, I think it would be helpful
最先设定一些分类
if, like, we started out with a bunch of categories,
-然后  -我们不能让它显得枯燥
- and then... - But we don't want to make it seem dry, you know?
不能让人觉得
We don't want to make it feel like
这是谁都能整理出来的
anyone could have organized this.
是啊  这点子太蠢了
Right. Yeah, it's a dumb idea.
不不  你所做的的优秀之处
No, no, what's so great about what you've done
在于其亲力亲为的感觉
is its personal touch,
感觉好像有人在另一端
the feeling that there is a person on the other side,
为你制造这一体验
creating this experience for you.
妈妈知道吗
Mom know about this?
不  她还不知道
No, she does not yet,
但我会来把这事告诉她
but I will be the one to give her that information,
谢谢了
thank you very much.
我能看吗
Can I watch?
我们要不要
Why don't we go, uh,
去纽约州北做洞穴探险
caving in upstate New York, you know, spelunking?
你在说胡话呢
You're literally shouting nonsense.
我有一堆资料
I got all this stuff, you know,
现在又有时间了
and -- and I've got time now.
我们该去冒险
We should go on an adventure.
我不想去山洞
I don't want to go to a cave.
那海莉呢
Well, look, Haley...
洞穴探险
...spelunking?
记得你做的那个关于钟乳石的项目吗
You remember that project you did about stalactites?
你想做什么我都行  爸爸
I'm cool wit whatever you want, Dad.
那件T恤衫  好酷
Oh, that T-shirt. That's wild,
我来的路上还在听仪式乐队
I was listening to Ritual on the way over here.
别费劲了
Please don't try.
去杰克逊霍尔飞钓呢
Wh-What about fly-fishing in Jackson Hole?
有人刚给我发了新链接加入我们的索引
Someone just sent me a new link to put in our index.
是...色青屋
It's, um, Smuth-ut.
琼妮  我们其实需要你的意见
You know, Joanie, we could actually use your input here.
什么样的网站会让你觉得很酷
What would make a website seem, you know, cool to you?
我觉得酷的是
Well, I think it's pretty cool
"美国最搞笑家庭视频"里
on "America's Funniest Home Videos"
有人被袭蛋
when guys get hit in the nuts.
好主意
That's a great idea.
好像是个建筑方面的
It's like some kind of construction thing.
我们该做这个  阿帕拉契山径
We should do this. The Appalachian Trail!
明年夏天
Next summer.
我们可以去徒步缅因州百里荒野
We can do the hundred-mile wilderness of Maine!
-糟糕  -天呐
- Oh, n-- - Oh, my God.
-快关掉  -抱歉  我在关
- Take down that... - Sorry. I'm taking it down!
关掉  关掉
Turn it off! Shut it down. Shut it --
-真棒  -对不起
- Yeah! - I'm sorry.
-关掉  -还有个脑袋
- Turn it off. - Oh, there's another head!
关掉
Take it off!
-还有个脑袋  -遮住眼睛
- There's another head. - Hide your eyes.
-我没在看  -她太娇贵了
- I'm not looking! - She's too precious, you guys.
放开我
Get off of me!
天呐
God.
听着  这太不体面了
Okay, look, that is inappropriate.
嗯
Yeah.
好
Yes, uh...
嗯  我们下周坐下谈谈吧
Yeah, let's sit down next week and talk about it.
我会让谭雅
I'll have Tanya
艾什莉打电话告诉你时间
or -- um, Ashley give you a call with times.
好的  你也是  再见
Okay. You, too. Bye.
你刚刚在跟摇滚小子说什么呢
What were you and, uh, Richie Sambora talking about?
他的暑期计划
His summer vacation plans.
那肯定很好玩吧
Oh, well, that must have been riveting.
别再说崔普了
Stop talking about Trip.
我不想再说他了
I don't want to talk about Trip anymore.
好吧
Okay.
他是个人才  还是公司的合伙人  唐娜
He is an asset and a partner in this firm, Donna.
这我知道
Yeah, I understand that.
我想我只是想确保
I guess I was just trying to make sure
会有人支持我
that someone had my back.
你知道这办公室是个男生俱乐部
You know this office is a boys' club.
的确
It is a boys' club,
而我还是在没人帮助的情况下当上了执行合伙人
and I made managing partner without anyone holding my hand.
他有优势吗  当然
Does he have an advantage? Of course he does.
但那跟你无关
But that has nothing to do with you.
你在这里的成功是基于结果的
Your success here is based on results,
我觉得你把团队打得鼻青脸肿
and I don't think you kicking the crap out of your team
是得不到结果的
is the way to get 'em.
我是来告诉你
I came in here to tell you
你流浪者团队里那个女生
that your girl from the Rover team --
她刚刚在楼梯井里哭呢
she was crying in the stairwell just now.
你或许该考虑采取温柔点的手段
You might want to consider a lighter touch.
-好吧  我们开始吧  -好
- Okay. Here we go... - Okay.
-那个  -听着  我明白你们说策略的事
- So - Listen, I heard what you said about strategy,
-我  -抱歉  容我...
- and I-- - I'm sorry, let me --
我们最好先说
I think we should go first here.
很不幸  我们不知道怎么会出现这种情况
Unfortunately, we don't know how this happened,
但《电子游戏月刊》
but someone at Electronic Gaming Monthly
拿到了《朝圣者》
got a hold of Pilgrim.
开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
今天出来了一篇评论
A review came out today,
我们拿到了预售本
and we got our hands on an advanced copy.
怎么样
How is it?
老实说  不好
It wasn't good, to be honest.
我们都支持这款游戏
We were all rooting for this game,
你也知道我们多么
and you know how fond we are
喜欢你和你的一切作品
of you and all the work that you've done.
你们打算不发了吗
Are you just gonna sit on it?
以现在的样子发布
Releasing it in its current form
就目前而言不是可行策略
isn't a viable strategy at this point.
太疯狂了
That's crazy.
评论怎么说的
What did it say?
你自己看吧
I'll let you read it.
我保证
I promise,
我们的律师会去找评论人
our lawyers are gonna get into it with the reviewer,
不管是谁把游戏给了他  也会承担责任
and whoever gave him the game will be dealt with.
是我给他们的
I gave it to them.
我想修饰一下界面
I want to spruce up the interface --
不用太花哨  应该利落高效
not too slick, but it should be, like, clean and efficient.
而且我们该在各大留言板上推广一下
And we should spread awareness on the message boards.
还有平面广告  今后值得考虑一下
Print ads, too, might be worth a look down the road.
你对这个似乎真的很热衷
You seem really excited about this.
你该实现它
I mean, you should run with it.
当然了  我下定决心了
Absolutely. I'm committed to this.
不  我是说  你该接过去
No, I mean, uh, you should take it.
给海莉开张支票  然后接过去
Write Haley a check and -- and take it.
是因为色情屋的事吗
Is this about Smut Hut?
我会把我的电邮写成网站联络方式
I'll make my e-mail the contact for the site.
不不  不是那个
No, no. It's -- It's not.
就是
It's just, uh...
原因很多
it's a lot of things, okay?
我不确定我希望她做这个
I'm not sure that I want this for her.
好吧
Okay.
戈登
You know, Gordon...
我希望我们一起做的
...I want us to do this together.
你跟我一样
You can't sit still
-是个坐不住的人  -乔  我没闲坐着
- any more than I can. You know? - Joe, I haven't been sitting still.
我一直都忙里忙外地
I've been busting my ass, working on things,
经营着我在意的东西
things that I care about,
而且告诉你
and just to let you know,
我都没要你帮忙
I have been doing it without your help.
对此我很抱歉
And I'm sorry about that.
这是个大转变
It's a big shift,
而且
you know, and --
发生得很快
and it happened fast and --
你什么都没变  乔
Nothing's shifted for you, Joe.
你的眼睛一直盯着这个
You've had your eyes locked on this,
盯着网络
on the web, the whole time.
你逼迫人  乔
You push people, Joe.
在卡迪夫
You did it at Cardiff.
西方集团
You did it at WestGroup.
你一直都这么做
You do it all the time.
你决定了什么对一个公司或一个人好
You decide what's right for a company or a person
然后就不顾他们准没准备好  一个劲地逼迫他们
and you push them whether they're ready for it or not,
我现在就告诉你
and I can tell you right now,
海莉还没准备好
Haley's not ready for it.
该死
Oh, shit.
我该走了
I should go.
你不用破费的
Oh, you didn't have to do that.
崔普叫我把这个拿给你
Trip asked me to bring this to you.
邮包炸弹吗
Letter bomb?
我去把这个放进冰箱里
I'm gonna put this in the fridge.
需要我做什么吗
Do you need me to do anything?
不用
No, just...
给自己倒点东西吧
pour yourself something.
敲敲门
Knock, knock.
博斯  谢谢你来
Bos, thanks for coming.
当然了  这肯定好玩
Well, sure, it should be fun.
我觉得过意不去
I just felt bad.
我...一早上很不顺
I was such a -- I had a crappy morning.
我觉得...
I figured...
稍稍放松下能有利于鼓舞士气
a little unwinding would be good for morale.
没事  我懂的
No, look, I get it.
但那些孩子要被晃出毛病了
The kids are gonna get whiplash, though,
你前一刻对他们凶巴巴的
well, you laying 'em out one minute
接下来又请他们来吃晚饭
and invitin' them to dinner the next.
但是
But...
你知道如果流浪者有什么问题
You know you can always come directly to me
你总可以直接来找我的吧
if there's ever any trouble with Rover, right?
-什么问题  -有人吗
- Trouble? - Hello!
他们来了
There they are!
进来吧
Come on in!
你们  自己找点喝的吧
You can, uh, grab yourself something to drink,
还有...过来抱一个
and there's -- Oh, come here.
披萨就来了
Pizza's on the way.
-这房子真好  -看啊
- It's a really nice home. - Look at that.
-解百纳  威士忌  -不了  谢谢
- Cab? Scotch? - No, thank you.
"呆板  混乱"
"A ponderous mess."
"豪伊完全出于自大
"It's Howe's ego-encasing strategy
让人们根本无从理解游戏
to put any understanding of the game completely out of reach,
而当用户无法领悟  又责怪他们
and then blame the user when they are unable to grasp it.
我向读者们保证  你们没错过什么
Let me assure my readers, you are not missing anything,
这款游戏根本不好玩"
for this game simply isn't any fun."
你为什么要发给他们
Why did you send it to 'em?
我以为它很好
I thought it was good.
这只是一个评论
It's just one review.
不是的  这是唯一的评论  这是...
It's not. It's the review. It's --
天呐  焦点小组  测试
God, the focus-group testing --
你都不喜欢
even you didn't like it.
我还没打完呢
I haven't finished it yet.
他们怎么说的  怎么打算的
What did they say, what -- what -- what's...
他们要拿走游戏  拿走代码
They're gonna take the game, take the code,
给别人  重新编排
give it to some guy, retool it,
我不知道  可能改成大胸雇佣兵
add -- I don't know -- probably a big-titted mercenary
砍人的头吧
decapitating people or something.
看着我
Look at me.
你有一堆的点子
You are full of ideas,
你会制作很多受人喜爱的游戏
and you are going to make a lot of games that people love.
你得把这事放下
You need to put this behind you,
重新开始  向前看
start fresh, and move on.
这对我没那么简单
It's not that easy for me.
我得去  喘口气
I need to, uh, take a breather,
自己待会儿  好吗
just be by myself for a sec, okay?
我著名的沙拉来了
Well, here comes my famous salad.
里面有糖核桃  秘诀在这里
There's candied walnuts in it. That's the secret.
我不会说出去
Well, it's safe with me.
小猴子
Monkey.
一切都好吗
Everything okay?
不好  爸爸好浑
No. Dad's being a dick.
我今晚能待这儿吗
Can I stay here tonight?
当然
Yeah, sure.
琼妮  这是大家  各位  这是琼妮
Joanie, this is everyone. Everyone, Joanie.
你想来点披萨吗
Do you want some pizza?
她做了她著名的沙拉
She made her famous salad.
她那么说了吗  她"著名的沙拉"
Did she call it her "famous salad"?
今天在公司  我找到了个网站
At work today, I found a website --
各位  我们不用谈工作的
Guys, we don't have to talk about work.
这就是消遣  你们不是在工作
This is fun. You're not on the clock.
要是不说工作
Well, if we're not gonna talk about work,
那我们说什么
what we gonna talk about?
好吧  好  抱歉
Okay. All right. I'm sorry.
我有事想说
Well, I have an update.
我们之前的问题
The problem we were having,
总统的问题
the -- the president problem...
西塞尔有办法解决了
...Cecil came up with a fix.
临时的解决办法
A -- A temporary solution.
维拉实施了基本推理法则
Vera implemented basic inference rules
补充了布林逻辑
that complement the Boolean logic,
这样当你输入"总统"即使没打"克林顿"
so when you type "president" without "Clinton,"
也能得到相关结果
you get relevant results.
"岩石/摇滚"会得到攀岩和音乐
"Rock" will give you climbing and music,
"鸡"能得到帕尔玛干酪
"Chicken" will give you Parmesan.
这是个创可贴  但暂时可用
It's a Band-Aid, but it works for now.
那如果我们输入"餐桌对话"呢
Well, what if we typed in "dinner-table conversation"?
好吧
Okay.
好吧  我本不想这么做的
All right, I didn't want to have to do this,
但显然  没办法了
but apparently, I do.
小心  小心
Look out. Look out.
重武器来了
Here come the big guns.
我去
Oh, shit.
但我们必须放松下来
But we are going to relax.
我们要好好开心
We are gonna have fun.
我们都要忘记
We are all going to forget about
我今早多混蛋
what a jerk I was this morning.
-我能来一杯吗  -拉倒吧
- Can I have one? - Oh, yeah, right.
我不用了  谢谢
I'm okay, thanks.
不行  这是强制的
No. Unh-unh. This is mandatory.
除非你怀孕了
Unless you're pregnant,
我不想再听你说什么了
I don't want to hear another word about it.
天呐
Oh, my -- Oh, my God.
-真抱歉  -没事的
- I'm -- I'm so sorry. - No. It's okay.
真厉害  妈妈
Nice one, Mom.
那么...
Well, I guess...
我们有孩子了
We're pregnant.
什么
What?
恭喜  老天爷啊
Well, congratulations, for God's sake.
-谢谢  -干杯
- Thank you. - Salud!
天呐  我太过分了
Oh, my God. That was so rude.
真的没事
It's completely okay, please.
好吧  那至少允许我祝一杯酒
Okay, well, let me at least propose a toast, then,
我刚刚太过分了  侵犯了你们的隐私
after that horrible, invasive, horribleness.
我记得我怀着那家伙的时候
I remember when I was pregnant with that one --
她最喜欢我提这个了
she loves it when I do this --
我当时在睿侠工作  好能打折买零件
I was working at Radio Shack so I could get a discount on parts,
琼妮的爸爸和我当时在搭建第一台电脑
Joanie's dad and I were building our first computer,
我特别害怕被老板发现
and I was terrified that my boss would find out.
于是我去了二手店
So I went to a thrift store
买来了我能找到的最大最臃肿的毛衣
and I bought just the biggest, baggiest sweaters I could find.
总之  几个月后
Anyway, months go by,
我以为我完全唬住了那人
and I think I've got this guy completely fooled,
然后有一天  他非常随意地靠过来
and then one day, he leans over to me very casually,
他说
and he says,
"转眼间  他们就会长大
"Before you know it, they'll be grown.
你要抓住每个机会吻那个宝宝"
You kiss that baby every chance you get."
他是对的
Well, he was right.
总之
Anyway,
你不用在我身边穿大号衣服
you don't have to wear any giant sweaters around me...
但是
...but...
你们要抓住每个机会吻那个宝宝
You kiss that baby every chance you get.
我真为你们高兴
I'm so happy for you.
干杯
Cheers.
敬吻宝宝
Here's to baby-smooching, then.
-敬吻宝宝  -好啊
- To baby-smooching. - Sure!
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Salud.
干杯
Cheers.
你在这儿啊  你个小混蛋
There you are, you little shit.
抱歉  我只是需要个地方玩
Sorry, I just needed someplace to play.
我这就走
I'll get out of your hair.
你在玩《毁灭战士》
You playing Doom?
嗯
Yeah.
看来这是未来的趋势了
Yeah, I guess this is where everything's going.
杀光一切
You just... kill everything.
挺赞的  是吧
It's pretty awesome, right?
嗯
Yeah.
你玩过吗
You've played?
嗯  还打得挺好
Yeah. Pretty good at it, too.
一战到死
Deathmatch?
天呐
God!
戈登  快动
Gordon, move!
你知道游戏的目标是不死吧
You do know the object of the game is to not die, right?
你个混蛋
You bastard!
那个  我
So, I, um...
很遗憾你离婚了
I'm sorry about the divorce.
嗯  谢谢
Yeah. Thank you.
这是有种宣泄感
There is something cathartic about it.
当然了
You bet your ass.
你终归离婚了啊
It's that you get to be divorced afterwards.
我是指游戏
I was talking about the game.
是啊  嗯
Yeah, yeah.
你感觉怎么样
So, how you dealing with all of it?
挺好
Good.
对于我和唐娜
You know, for me and Donna, it was, uh...
最后的那几个月
you know, those last few months,
程序  解开一切的羁绊
the process and just getting everything untangled.
-那  -天呐
- It was... - Oh, my God.
很艰难的
It was really hard.
嗯  我能想象  还有孩子
Yeah, I can imagine, with kids.
对于我和汤姆  这...
For Tom and I, it's been, you know,
已经是最好的情况了吧  但还是...
as good as it can be, I guess, but still, it's...
这提醒我了  你收到了个包裹
That reminds me, um, you got a package out there.
乔忘记带走了
Joe forgot to take it with him.
我...好吧
I -- Okay.
我走时带着
I'll take it on my way out.
乔怎么样了
So, how's Joe?
挺好
Good.
谁知道呢  但是现在
I mean, you know, who knows, but right now...
挺好
good.
你们还会再合作吗
Think you guys'll ever work together again?
不会
No.
那是雷区
That's a minefield.
他对彗星的事非常激动
He, uh, is really pumped about this Comet thing, though.
他给我看了  真的很酷
He showed me. It's really cool.
我真不敢相信小海莉...
I just can't believe little Haley is --
嗯  我叫他自己继续了
Yeah, I told him to move on without us.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know, I...
琼妮说是因为我嫉妒
Joanie says it's 'cause I'm jealous.
她说对了吗
Is she right?
或许吧
Maybe.
或许我是嫉妒他们有个新点子
Maybe I'm just jealous that they had a new idea.
我绝对嫉妒
I mean, I'm definitely jealous
我已经不年轻了
that I'm not a kid anymore.
那么长久以来  一直担心
You know, all that time you spend worrying about
把精力浪费在错误的项目
wasting it on the wrong project,
或错误的人上
or the -- you know, the wrong person.
很难想到比跟她一起做一件
It's hard to think of a better way to spend your time
她在乎的事更值得做的事
than working with her on something she cares about.
真希望我爸爸能看到我有一技之长
I wish my dad could have seen me be good at something.
听着  你十几岁的女儿想跟你共处
Look, your teenage daughter wants to hang out with you.
这可不是常有的事
That doesn't happen.
我知道  但是
Yeah, I know, but...
你不用担心她变成我这样
You don't have to worry about her turning out like me.
她有两位很棒的家长照顾着她
She has two awesome parents looking out for her.
你还有个杯子做证明
You've even got a mug to prove it.
卡梅伦
Cameron!
-盒子  -抱歉
- Box. - Sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡梅
Hey, Cam?
嗯
Yeah?
要是我的女儿变得像你也不会很糟的
It wouldn't be so bad if my girls turned out like you.
如果真是那样  我会为她们骄傲的
I'd be proud of 'em if they did,
作为父亲
you know, as a dad.
老天爷啊
Geez, Louise.
海莉做的东西挺酷  是吧
Haley's project's pretty cool, right?
非常酷
It's very cool.
嗯
Yeah.
该死
Oh, shit!
不要
No!
怎么了
What's going on?
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
嗯
Yeah.
你想跟乔一起做彗星吗
Do you want to work on Comet with Joe?
嗯
Yeah.
那有些条件
Then there are conditions.
一  别让他
One, you don't let him
或其他人欺负你
or anyone else push you around.
你要是有什么点子  就说出来
Okay, if you have an idea, you say so.
如果你不喜欢一个点子  也要说出来
If you don't like an idea, you say so, okay?
二  这是一种乐趣
Number two, this is fun, okay?
如果它不再有乐趣了
And the second that it stops being fun,
你告诉我  我们都离开
you say so, and we both walk away.
好
Okay.
-保证吗  -保证
- Promise? - Promise.
发誓
Cross your heart, hope to die?
嗯  发誓
Yeah, all that stuff.
那好
Okay.
你去哪
Where are you going?
我们该开始了
We should get started.
亲爱的  现在是半夜
Sweetheart, it's midnight.
我们还有工作要做呢
Well, we have work to do.
好吧
Okay.
那好
All right.
你关于分类的想法
Your idea about categorizing...
挺聪明的
...it's smart.
从那里开始吧
So... let's start there.
好
Okay.
大家简直对他们服服帖帖
They had the crowd eating out of their hand.
黛安也在的
I mean, Diane was there.
-他们很圆滑  -流浪者呢
- They're slick. - And Rover?
我昨晚请了全队去我家
I had the whole team over last night
我们好开诚布公
so we could open up the lines of communication,
聊聊工作之外的事
bat stuff around outside the office,
非常顺利
went really well.
那个网站的目标是什么
What's the endgame with that site?
怎么说
In what sense?
成品
The finished product --
我就是好奇你的设想是什么
I'm just curious how you're seeing that.
是你每次上网登录的第一个网站
It's the first site you visit every time you're online.
是能带你去你想去的地方的页面
It's the page that gets you where you wanna go --
抱歉  有什么问题吗
I'm sorry, is there a problem?
抱歉  我就是想让你注意一件事
No, sorry, I just wanted to flag something for you,
但我们可以稍后绕回来
but we can circle back to that later.
我去你办公室说
I'll swing by your office.
没事  如果你有事要说  就请说吧
Oh, no. If you have something to share, be my guest.
班基给我发了一个网站链接
Benji sent me a link to a site
感觉可能是个类似的理念
that feels like it might be operating in a similar space.
只想确保你知道
Just wanted to make sure you were aware.
班基  帮帮忙  去查查彗星是谁的
Benji, do me a favor and see who's behind Comet.
或许可以想想办法
Maybe there's a play to be made there.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不  我来吧
Oh, no. I can get that.
其实  有件事
I actually had one thing
我想跟你说两句
I wanted to talk to you about real quick.
好啊
Oh, good.
我也有事  但你先说吧
Me, too, but you go first.
单位有人给我看了彗星网  还是什么的
Someone at work showed me the comet list or Comet?
嗯  你觉得如何
Yeah. Yeah. What do you think?
-不错  -是吗
- It's good. - Yeah?
很不错  就是
It's really good, I just --
我们有个项目  看上去
we have something, a play that looks like
会跟这个形成竞争
it could be part of the competitive landscape,
我想告诉你一声
and I wanted to make sure you knew.
跟这个形成竞争
Part of the competitive landscape?
是一个搜索算法
It's a search algorithm,
基本上索引了网络  让它可搜索
basically indexing the web, making it searchable.
起初是个医疗索引软件
It started as a medical indexing software,
他们改用在了网络上
and they shifted into web.
是他们吗
They shifted.
什么时候
When?
不久之前
A little while ago.
这是团队的点子
Look, it's the idea the team came to.
出于好意  我想告诉你
I wanted to tell you as a courtesy.
那我第一次提到我们的索引项目时
Well, why didn't you tell me as a courtesy
你怎么没好意把这告诉我
when I mentioned our indexing project the first time?
你当时告诉我的是乔在写网址
Well, you told me that Joe was writing down websites.
你没说你们要以此建立公司
You didn't tell me you were building a company out of it.
你要跟我们竞争
So you're competing with us?
我们不非得的
Well, we don't have to be.
我相信我能劝说合伙人们收购你们
I'm sure I can talk the partners into buying you out.
收购我们
Buy us?
我们怎么不收购你们
Why don't we buy you?
戈登  你跟我们争不过
Oh, well, Gordon, you can't compete with us.
你们的资本没有我们雄厚
You're not capitalized the way we are.
你们打不了持久战的  相信我
You don't have the staying power, believe me.
是海莉的网站
It's Haley's website.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
海莉的彗星  这是她做的
Haley's Comet -- she made the thing.
我们要一起建造
We're building it together.
你打算什么时候告诉我的
When were you gonna tell me this?
-现在  -吃第二道甜点时吗
- Right now. - Oh, over second dessert?
得了  就好像你没拖着
Yeah, like you weren't holding out
你偷了我们点子的消息才说似的
on the news that you stole our idea.
得了  我才没偷什么
Oh, please, I didn't steal anything.
现在大家都开始做这个了
You know everyone's getting into this right now.
你不能瞒着我关于我们女儿的事
You can't keep things from me about our daughter.
事情就这么发生了
This just happened.
就这么发生了
It just happened.
我现在告诉你了  我们吃饭就为了这个
I'm telling you now. That's what these dinners are for.
你想每晚跟我吃晚饭吗
You want to have dinner with me every night?
并不想  我试了15年
Well, no, not really. I tried that for 15 years,
但还是没有得到全部的信息
didn't exactly get all the information then, either.
天呐  我们又开始旧事重提了  是吧
Oh, God. Yeah, we're really playin' all the hits, aren't we?
这种决定你无权自己做主
This is not the kind of decision you get to make on your own.
听我说  是海莉建的
Listen to me -- Haley built it, okay?
我们在帮她做大
And we're helping her make it into something more,
她很喜欢它
and she loves it, okay?
你想粉碎了它  随你
You want to crush that, go ahead.
但等你告诉她时
But when you break the news to her,
一定告诉她原因  妈妈的山寨公司
make sure you to tell her why -- that Mommy's knock-off company
争不过她建造的那个
couldn't compete with the one that she built.
戈登  这是个坏主意  听我的
Gordon, this is a bad idea, I'm telling you.
流浪者有全公司的支持
Rover has the full weight of the firm behind it,
它有势头  我现在想都阻止不了了
it's got momentum, and I couldn't stop it now if I tried.
听着  我们要建个网站
Listen. We're building the site.
随你怎么做吧
You do whatever you think is right.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
收拾行李
I'm unpacking.